Inventory of the Edward J. Rozek papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1950-2009 (Boxes 3-38)
  - Kazimierza Sabbat, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - Bill Saleh, 2005 (Box-folder 31: 5)
  - Steve Samson, 1994-2005 (Box-folder 31: 6)
    Includes two CDs promoting Liberty University.
  - Lewis Sawin, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 31: 7)
  - Saudi Arabia, letter to Prince Saoud Al-Faisal, Foreign Minister of Saudi Arabia, 1981 (Box-folder 31: 8)
  - Leonard Schapiro, 1968-1983 (Box-folder 31: 9)
  - Daniel L. Schaefer, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 31: 10)
  - Eleanor Schafly, 1988 (Box-folder 31: 11)
  - Robert Schwartz, 1999 (Box-folder 31: 12)
  - James F. Scott, 1988 (Box-folder 31: 13)
  - Richard Sears, 1957-2004 (Box-folder 31: 14)
  - Bill and Julie Shade, 2000-2006 (Box-folder 31: 15)
  - Shah of Iran, 1991 (Box-folder 31: 16)
  - Roy Shore, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 31: 17)
  - Sievers/Ellins, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Marek and Iza Sikora, 1993-2006 (Box-folder 32: 2)
  - William Simon, "To Reopen the American Mind,", 1988 (Box-folder 32: 3)
  - William Sinclair, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 32: 4)
  - Father Robert Sirico, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - General John Singlaub, 1979 (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - Dr. Miroslav Sladek, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 32: 7)
  - Smith Richardson Foundation, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 32: 8)
  - Solidarity, 2007 (Box-folder 32: 9)
    Newspaper articles in Polish.
  - Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 32: 10)
  - Solzhenitsyn Society, examples of bylaws, 1975 (Box-folder 32: 11)
  - Solzhenitsyn Society newsletter, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 32: 12)
  - South Africa correspondence, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 32: 13)
  - South African documents, 1977-1986 (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - Dean Peter Spear, 1997 (Box-folder 33: 2)
  - Special letters, 2005 (Box-folder 33: 3)
  - Arthur Spitzer, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 33: 4)
  - Sergei B. Stankevich, 1993 (Box-folder 33: 5)
  - J. Stanfield, 1984 (Box-folder 33: 6)
  - Bob Starks, 2006 (Box-folder 33: 7)
  - Professor Andrzej Stelmachowski, 1991 (Box-folder 33: 8)
  - George Stewart, 1956-2001 (Box-folder 33: 9)
  - Zeph Stewart, 1974-2008 (Box-folder 33: 10)
  - Colonel Charles Stibrany, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 33: 11)
  - Thomas G. Storey, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 33: 12)
  - Ronya Stojko-Lozynsky, undated (Box-folder 33: 13)
  - Senator Stromer Kearney College, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 33: 14)
  - Students for a Better America, 1996 (Box-folder 33: 15)
  - Gil and Patti Summers, 2005 (Box-folder 33: 16)
  - Jan and Teresa Suchcitz, 2001 (Box-folder 33: 17)
  - Bill Sullivan, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 33: 18)
  - Larry Summers Polish TV, 2003 (Box-folder 33: 19)
  - Wieslawa Surazska, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 33: 20)
  - John Suthers, 2007 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Carol Suzuki, 1977 (Box-folder 34: 2)
  - Clint Talbott, 2005 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  - Pal Tar, Ambassador of Hungary, 1993 (Box-folder 34: 4)
  - Pat Taylor, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 34: 5)
  - Edward Teller, 1986-2003 (Box-folder 34: 6)
  - Ewa Thompson, The Sarmatian Review, 1998-2005 (Box-folder 34: 7)
  - Sir Robert Thompson, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 34: 8)
  - Robert N. Thompson, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 34: 9)
  - Count Nikolai Tolstoy, 1986-1999 (Box-folder 34: 10-11)
  - Trevor-Roper, Professor H. R., 1974-1988 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - William A. Trine, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 35: 2)
  - Ukrainian Quarterly, 1979 (Box-folder 35: 3)
  - Otto Ulc, undated (Box-folder 35: 4)
  - USIC Educational Foundation, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 35: 5)
  - Duke de Valderano, 1985-1993 (Box-folder 35: 6)
  - Marilyn Van Derbur, 1960-1990 (Box-folder 35: 7)
  - Venerable Order of St. John, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 35: 8)
  - Jack Vickers, 1979 (Box-folder 35: 9)
  - Vivas, Eliseo, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 35: 10)
  - Rick Volpe, 2002 (Box-folder 35: 11)
  - Jacek von Hennaberg, 1968-2001 (Box-folder 35: 12)
  - Vrabek, 2007-2008 (Box-folder 35: 13)
  - Anna Walentynowicz, 2001 (Box-folder 35: 14)
  - Lech Walesa, 1998 (Box-folder 35: 15)
  - Richard L. Walker, 1973-1999 (Box-folder 35: 16)
  - Thaddeus Frances Walkowicz, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 35: 17)
  - Lewis W. Walt, 1972 (Box-folder 35: 18)
  - President Arnold Weber, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 35: 19)
  - Caspar W. Weinberger, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 35: 20)
  - Pamela White, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 35: 21)
  - Chris Whitney, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - Charles Wick, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 36: 2)
  - Wielgat, 2007-2009 (Box-folder 36: 3)
    Includes one CD.
  - Stephen F. Williams, 1985 (Box-folder 36: 4)
  - Verna Winegar, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 36: 5)
  - General David Winn, 1985-2009 (Box-folder 36: 6)
  - Nancy Winters, 2006-2008 (Box-folder 36: 7)
  - Bertram D. Wolfe, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 36: 8-11)
  - Bertram D. Wolfe, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 37: 1-6)
  - Bertram D. Wolfe, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 38: 1-2)
  - Rostow Review, Allied Wartime Diplomacy (AWD) (Box-folder 38: 3)
  - Allied Wartime Diplomacy, 2nd edition, 1989 (Box-folder 38: 4)
  - AWD, Orlowski translation, undated (Box-folder 38: 5)
  - Essay on Czechoslovakia, undated (Box-folder 38: 6)
  - Rozek speeches, 2003-2007 (Box-folder 38: 7)
  - Memos, articles, and letters, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 38: 8)
- University of Colorado Files, 1960-2005 (Boxes 39-40)
  Memos, correspondence, and files from and regarding the University of Colorado.
  - Correspondence regarding cross listing/discrimination, 1992 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Memos to Ekstrand, 1992 (Box-folder 39: 2)
  - 1989 salary dispute (Box-folder 39: 3)
  - Salary inequity, 1978-1985 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - James Scarritt, 1981 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Teaching, important letters, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 39: 6)
  - Student evaluation, 1966-1982 (Box-folder 39: 7)
  - Rainey Committee, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 39: 8)
  - Surazska memo, 1991 (Box-folder 39: 9)
  - Dispute with Harry Shull, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 39: 10)
  - Salary and promotion disputes, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 40: 1)
  - Awards, 1970-2005 (Box-folder 40: 2)
  - Trip to Reagan Presidential Library, 1991 (Box-folder 40: 3)
  - Trip to Poland, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 40: 4)
  - Trip to Eastern Europe, 1990 (Box-folder 40: 5)
    Includes postcards and pamphlets from Berlin.
  - Trip to Taiwan, 1988 (Box-folder 40: 6)
  - Trip to Korea, 1986 (Box-folder 40: 7)
- Writings, 1968-2009 (Boxes 41-46)
  Original drafts and writings by Edward Rozek. Many drafts are undated.
  - "Problems in American Foreign Policy,", undated (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - "The Professional Responsibility of a Lawyer in a Democracy,", undated (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - "The Price of Freedom,", 1970 (Box-folder 41: 3)
  - "Nuclear Weapons: Deterrent in Defense of Freedom with Justice,", 1983 (Box-folder 41: 4)
  - "Economic Integration: The CMEA,", undated (Box-folder 41: 5)
  - "Why Marxism Was Adopted by the Russians,", undated (Box-folder 41: 6)
  - "The Intellectual Transformation of Norman Podhoretz,", 1981 (Box-folder 41: 7)
  - "Nationalism in Stalin's Political Strategy and Ideology,", undated (Box-folder 41: 8)
  - "Gomulka and Polish National Communism,", undated (Box-folder 41: 9)
  - "Foreign Policy Under Andropov,", 1983 (Box-folder 41: 10)
  - "What Is the Role of the Conservative in a Modern Bureaucratic Society?,", 1972 (Box-folder 41: 11)
  - "Revolutionary Upheavals in Eastern Europe,", undated (Box-folder 41: 12)
  - 1976 Institute, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 41: 13)
    Correspondence from The Institute for the Study of Comparative Politics and Ideologies.
  - 1978 Institute (Box-folder 41: 14)
  - Thank you letters, 1979 (Box-folder 41: 15)
  - Thank you letters, 1980 (Box-folder 41: 16)
  - 1978 Institute (Box-folder 41: 17)
  - 1977 Institute (Box-folder 41: 18)
  - Contract with Cornbridge, 1991-2003 (Box-folder 42: 1)
  - "Education and Freedom,", 1997 (Box-folder 42: 2)
  - Allied Wartime Diplomacy translation, Golberg/Orlowsky, 2007 (Box-folder 42: 3)
  - Patriotic emails, 2003-2007 (Box-folder 42: 4)
  - Polish obituaries and translations, 2009 (Box-folder 42: 5)
  - Tammy Fitzgerald's eulogy, 2009 (Box-folder 42: 6)
  - Rozek, short biography, 2008 (Box-folder 42: 7)
    Contains information about his life, including curriculum vitae and extended family tree.
  - University of Colorado (CU-Boulder) articles, 2006 (Box-folder 42: 8)
  - Talbott, CU, Boulder Camera, 2006 (Box-folder 42: 9)
  - Tygodnik Solidarnosc letter, 2006 (Box-folder 42: 10)
  - Tragedja Polskiego Stronnictwa Ludowego, 2006 (Box-folder 42: 11)
  - Paul Levitt, "New Godfather," Boulder Camera, 2006 (Box-folder 42: 12)
  - "Anatomy of Hypocrisy,", 2008 (Box-folder 42: 13)
  - "Academic Doubletalk,", 2008 (Box-folder 42: 14)
  - "Political Imbalance at CU Can and Must Be Corrected,", 2008 (Box-folder 42: 15)
  - Bensen article, 2008 (Box-folder 42: 16)
  - "Mr. Brown Wants to Go to D.C.,", 2007 (Box-folder 42: 17)
  - Rumsfeld dismissal, 2007 (Box-folder 42: 18)
  - "Students Fail U.S. History,", 2006 (Box-folder 42: 19)
  - "Regents Temper Tantrum Doesn't Alter Facts,", 2006 (Box-folder 42: 20)
  - Post-Mortem of presidential search, 2007 (Box-folder 42: 21)
  - "Buffaloed Logic,", 2006 (Box-folder 42: 22)
  - Regents, 2006 (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - "Most Neglected and Exploited Profession,", 2005 (Box-folder 43: 2)
  - "Blame Regents for CU's Decline,", 2005 (Box-folder 43: 3)
  - "Presidential List Had Four Non-Politicians,", 2005 (Box-folder 43: 4)
  - Enron letter, Boulder Camera, 2005 (Box-folder 43: 5)
  - "CU Salaries,", 2005 (Box-folder 43: 6)
  - "CU Needs Radical Top to Bottom Reform,", 2005 (Box-folder 43: 7)
  - "A Hypocritical Allusion to Joe,", 2005 (Box-folder 43: 8)
  - "Academic Elephantiasis,", undated (Box-folder 43: 9)
  - "In Defense of Rumsfeld,", 2004 (Box-folder 43: 10)
  - Sarmatian Review of Polish Yearbook of Foreign Affairs, 2005 (Box-folder 43: 11)
  - Bob Schaffer, 2004 (Box-folder 43: 12)
  - "Collaborators and Appeasers of Tyrants,", undated (Box-folder 43: 13)
  - "Edward Rozek: A Student's Tribute,", undated (Box-folder 43: 14)
  - East-West trade, 1977 (Box-folder 43: 15)
  - "The Foreign Affairs 50-Year Bibliography,", 1972 (Box-folder 43: 16)
    Includes a statement about Edward Rozek's book, Allied Wartime Diplomacy.
  - "The Price of Freedom,", 1970 (Box-folder 43: 17)
  - "An Open Letter to Republican Governors,", 1968 (Box-folder 43: 18)
  - "Bridge Building Between East and West,", 1963-1967 (Box-folder 43: 19)
  - Article by Rozek, 1958 (Box-folder 43: 20)
  - "The Winning Weapon, ", undated (Box-folder 43: 21)
  - Review of The New Class, undated (Box-folder 43: 22)
  - Untitled manuscript, undated (Box-folder 43: 23)
  - "Dialectical and Historical Materialism in the Bolshevik System,", undated (Box-folder 43: 24)
  - "The Price of Freedom" speech transcript, 2003 (Box-folder 44: 1)
  - Article, 2003 (Box-folder 44: 2)
  - Polish newspaper, 2003 (Box-folder 44: 3)
  - Article by Rozek, 2003 (Box-folder 44: 4)
  - "Central Europe at the Brink of Disaster,", 2003 (Box-folder 44: 5)
  - Article by Rozek, 2003 (Box-folder 44: 6)
  - The Trail-Gazette article regarding Rozek, 2002 (Box-folder 44: 7)
  - Lincoln Day dinner speech, 2002 (Box-folder 44: 8)
  - UNC Board of Trustees, 2002 (Box-folder 44: 9)
  - Polish article and newspaper, 2001 (Box-folder 44: 10)
  - Czas Ucieka, 2002 (Box-folder 44: 11)
    Includes article in Polish.
  - Greeley Tribune articles, 2002 (Box-folder 44: 12)
  - Colorado Daily articles, 2002 (Box-folder 44: 13)
  - "Spectrum of Political Creeds and Parties,", undated (Box-folder 44: 14)
  - "Why Political Pluralism Should Exist in Higher Education,", undated (Box-folder 44: 15)
  - Article by Rozek, 1997 (Box-folder 44: 16)
    Scope and Contents
  - Pogarda dla trutniow, 2001 (Box-folder 44: 17)
  - Article by Rozek, 2001 (Box-folder 44: 18)
  - Article by Rozek, 2001 (Box-folder 44: 19)
  - Neville Chamberlain article in Polish newspaper, 2001 (Box-folder 44: 20)
  - Review of AWD, Professor Botestaw, 2000 (Box-folder 44: 21)
    Includes newspaper in Polish.
  - Webster's letter to Tribune, 2000 (Box-folder 44: 22)
  - Mirror article about Rozek, 2000 (Box-folder 44: 23)
  - Greeley Tribune, 2000 (Box-folder 44: 24)
  - Polish articles, 1998 (Box-folder 44: 25)
  - Colorado Daily article, 1998 (Box-folder 44: 26)
  - "Political Imbalance at Colorado University,", 1998 (Box-folder 44: 27)
  - Article by Rozek, 1998 (Box-folder 44: 28)
  - Colorado Daily, 1997 (Box-folder 44: 29)
  - Polish article, 1997 (Box-folder 44: 30)
  - "Campaign Finance Reform," Colorado Daily, 1997 (Box-folder 44: 31)
  - "American by Choice,", 1996 (Box-folder 44: 32)
  - Article by Edward Rozek, 1996 (Box-folder 44: 33)
  - Article by Edward Rozek, undated (Box-folder 44: 34)
  - Human events, 2000 (Box-folder 44: 35)
  - Ksawery Pruszynski, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - Djilao, Denver Post, 1995 (Box-folder 45: 2)
  - McNamara, Denver Post, 1995 May 3 (Box-folder 45: 3)
  - Gazeta Polska, 1995 April 13 (Box-folder 45: 4)
    Newspaper in Polish.
  - Roundtable, 1993 (Box-folder 45: 5)
  - Teaching profession, 1991 (Box-folder 45: 6)
  - Political hyenas, 1990 (Box-folder 45: 7)
  - "Disintegration of Soviet Empire Colorado Springs,", 1990 (Box-folder 45: 8)
  - Gorbachev Jaruzelski, Chicago, 1989 (Box-folder 45: 9)
  - Review of Eugene Wittkopf Beyond the Cold War, 1989 (Box-folder 45: 10)
  - Sidney Hook, 1989 (Box-folder 45: 11)
  - "Gorbachev's Psychological Blitzkrieg,", 1989 (Box-folder 45: 12)
  - "Gorbachev, Super PR Man USBIC,", 1989 (Box-folder 45: 13)
  - Writings, 1989 (Box-folder 45: 14)
    Articles in Polish.
  - Gorbachev's and Khrushchev's UN speeches, undated (Box-folder 45: 15)
  - "Glasnost: Fiction or Reality," survey, 1988 (Box-folder 45: 16)
  - "Orwell's Prophesy," "Silvers and Gold,", 1988 (Box-folder 45: 17)
  - Letter to Insight, 1988 (Box-folder 45: 18)
  - Improve Communism, Human Events, 1988 (Box-folder 45: 19)
  - "Mainland China and the Security of the Pacific,", 1988 (Box-folder 45: 20)
  - "Gorbachev's 70th Anniversary Speech," Denver Post, 1987 (Box-folder 45: 21)
  - Glasnost, 1987 (Box-folder 45: 22)
  - Sea Island, Georgia, "The Role of The University in the Survival of a Free Society,", 1987 (Box-folder 45: 23)
  - "Most Generous Nation," Denver Post, 1986 (Box-folder 45: 24)
  - Buultjens, Denver Post, 1985 (Box-folder 45: 25)
  - Larson, Denver Post, 1985 (Box-folder 45: 26)
  - Denver Post, 1985 March (Box-folder 45: 27)
  - Weinberger, Denver Post, 1983 (Box-folder 45: 28)
  - "U.S. Policy and Soviet Leadership," Denver Post, 1982 (Box-folder 45: 29)
  - "From Brezhnev to Andropov,", 1985 (Box-folder 45: 30)
  - "Nuclear Fear Mongers,", 1982 (Box-folder 45: 31)
  - "Reverse McCarthyism,", 1982 (Box-folder 45: 32)
  - Boulder Camera, education, 1982 (Box-folder 45: 33)
  - "Human Rights and Reagan's Foreign Policy,", 1982 (Box-folder 45: 34)
  - "Open Letter to Senator Hart,", undated (Box-folder 45: 35)
  - George Meany article, Boulder Camera, 1980 (Box-folder 46: 1)
  - "Beware of Henry,", undated (Box-folder 46: 2)
  - "The Switch Doctor,", 1982 (Box-folder 46: 3)
  - Salary survey in Daily, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 4)
  - Anti-Rozek letter, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 5)
  - Letter to Denver Post re Zakhem vs. Darwin, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 6)
  - Sertoma Freedom Banquet, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 7)
  - "Whitewashing the White House,", 1980 (Box-folder 46: 8)
  - Interview, American foreign policy, 1980 (Box-folder 46: 9)
  - Reagan, defense and foreign policy, 1980 (Box-folder 46: 10)
  - Review of The Real War by Richard Nixon, 1980 (Box-folder 46: 11)
  - Lincoln Day dinner speech, 1980 (Box-folder 46: 12)
  - "George Meany Warned Us," Boulder Camera, 1980 (Box-folder 46: 13)
  - "Reagan Names Advisors" Washington Post, 1980 (Box-folder 46: 14)
  - Denver Post, George Meany, 1980 (Box-folder 46: 15)
  - Letters to the Washington Post, 1979 (Box-folder 46: 16)
  - Kissinger architect, 1979 (Box-folder 46: 17)
  - Denver Post, Borcher's letters, 1979 (Box-folder 46: 18)
  - Reply to Carrigan, 1978 (Box-folder 46: 19)
  - "Communist Imperialism,", 1978 (Box-folder 46: 20)
  - Reply to Schroeder, 1978 (Box-folder 46: 21)
  - "Whitewash of Soviet Intent," Denver Post response to Adelman, 1978 (Box-folder 46: 22)
  - Human Events: "Helsinki Agreement Ignored by the Kremlin,", 1978 (Box-folder 46: 23)
  - "Captive Nations" speech, 1977 (Box-folder 46: 24)
  - "What America Means to Me,", 1976 (Box-folder 46: 25)
  - "Obligations of Citizenship,", 1972 (Box-folder 46: 26)
- Institute for the Study of Comparative Politics and Ideologies Materials, 1956-1997 (Boxes 47-50)
  Correspondence, memos, and other materials.
  - "Eastern European Communism,", 1984 (Box-folder 47: 1)
  - Contract controversy, 1997 (Box-folder 47: 2)
  - Activities and engagements, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 47: 3)
    Correspondence regarding travel for lectures.
  - Activities and engagements, 1992 (Box-folder 47: 4)
  - Annual reports, 1991 (Box-folder 47: 5)
  - Annual faculty reports, 1990 (Box-folder 47: 6)
  - Annual faculty reports, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 48: 1-4)
  - Annual reports, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 48: 5-7)
  - Annual reports, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 49: 1-2)
  - Annual faculty reports, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 49: 3-5)
  - Annual faculty report, 1956-1977 (Box-folder 50: 1-3)
  - Payroll, undated (Box-folder 50: 4)
  - Elizabeth MacParland, 1982-1997 (Box-folder 50: 5)
    Files concerning the wrongful termination and reinstatement of Elizabeth MacParland as Edward Rozek's Administrative Assistant.
  - Merit review proposal, 1984 (Box-folder 50: 6)
- Center for Science, Technology, and Political Thought Materials, 1973-1999 (Boxes 51-54)
  - Clippings, 1973 (Box-folder 51: 1-2)
  - John Wittemyer correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 51: 3)
  - Bernard A. Schriever, 1975 (Box-folder 51: 4)
  - Frank Shakespeare, 1974 (Box-folder 51: 5)
  - Royal (Dan) Sloan, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 51: 6)
  - John W. Terrill, 1974 (Box-folder 51: 7)
  - Frederick A. Wyatt, 1975 (Box-folder 51: 8)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 51: 9)
  - Land Use Conference speeches, 1975 (Box-folder 51: 10-11)
  - James Q. Brett, Land Use Conference speakers, 1975 (Box-folder 51: 12)
  - Conference on Land Use publicity, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 1)
  - Frank E. Harris, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 52: 2)
  - Arnold Hennig, 1974 (Box-folder 52: 3)
  - Leo A. Hoegh, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 52: 4)
  - Jack Orr, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 5)
  - William A. Rense, 1974 (Box-folder 52: 6)
  - Arthur A. Spitzer, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 7)
  - T.F. Walkowicz, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 52: 8)
  - Center for Science, Technology, and Political Thought minutes, Board minutes, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 9)
  - Minutes, Joint Meeting of the Board and Advisory Council, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 10)
  - Meeting of the Board, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 11)
  - Advisory Council, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 12)
  - Harold M. Agnew, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 52: 13)
  - John R. Alison, 1974 (Box-folder 52: 14)
  - Frederick S. Allen, 1974 (Box-folder 52: 15)
  - Vincent T. Ford, 1974 (Box-folder 52: 16)
  - James M. Gavin, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 52: 17)
  - Palmer Hoyt, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 18)
  - Lloyd J. King, 1973 (Box-folder 52: 19)
  - John H. Morse, 1974 (Box-folder 52: 20)
  - State of Colorado Certificate of Incorporation, 1973 (Box-folder 52: 21)
  - Insurance, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 22)
  - Standard proposal, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 23)
  - Executive Committee general correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 52: 24)
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1974 (Box-folder 52: 25)
  - Executive Committee, 1974 (Box-folder 52: 26)
  - Participant correspondence, 1977 (Box-folder 52: 27)
  - Publicity, 1977 (Box-folder 52: 28)
  - Lawrence Livermore Laboratory, 1973 (Box-folder 52: 29)
  - Site Selection Committee, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 52: 30)
  - Statement of Purpose, 1973 (Box-folder 52: 31)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1975 (Box-folder 52: 32)
  - Norman O. Booth, Secretary, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 52: 33)
  - Roseanne S. Ball, 1974 (Box-folder 52: 34)
  - Charlotte E. Cabbot, 1974 (Box-folder 52: 35)
  - Virginia Black, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 53: 1)
  - Erik T. Vartiainen, 1974 (Box-folder 53: 2)
  - Cartoons, circa 1970 (Box-folder 53: 3)
  - Allan C. Brownfeld's articles regarding the Conference on Détente, 1976 (Box-folder 53: 4)
  - "Conference on Détente Slams Communism,", 1976 (Box-folder 53: 5)
  - Kissinger newspaper clippings, 1976 (Box-folder 53: 6)
  - Ford-Carter Debates, 1976 (Box-folder 53: 7)
  - Intermountain Jewish News, 1976 (Box-folder 53: 8)
  - Tax forms for Center for Science Technology and Political Thought, 1986-1997 (Box-folder 53: 9)
  - "Fighting Commies with Professor Rozek,", 1976 (Box-folder 53: 10)
    Article about Rozek's many Institutes, Centers, and Societies.
  - Tax exemption letter, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 53: 11)
  - Center for Science, Technology, and Political Thought correspondence, 1999 (Box-folder 53: 12)
  - Center lists, 1994 (Box-folder 53: 13)
  - Minutes, 1973-1999 (Box-folder 53: 14)
  - Social Security census report, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 54: 1)
  - Miscellaneous documents, 1975 (Box-folder 54: 2)
  - Christian N. Barnard, 1975 (Box-folder 54: 3)
  - William Buckley, Jr. dinner, 1976 (Box-folder 54: 4)
  - Materials from Edward Teller Center, 1974 (Box-folder 54: 5)
  - Edward Teller speech, 1974 (Box-folder 54: 6)
  - Financial reports, 1974 (Box-folder 54: 7)
  - Solzhenitsyn Foundation correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 54: 8)
  - Symposium on Energy correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 54: 9)
  - Tri-State Fossil Fuels Energy Conference, KOSTKA, statements of expenses, 1974 (Box-folder 54: 10)
  - Energy Conference publicity, 1974 (Box-folder 54: 11)
  - Conference on Détente administrative matters, 1976 (Box-folder 54: 12)
  - Conference on Détente program/agenda, 1976 (Box-folder 54: 13)
  - Conference on Détente, Mefford, Warren, Mier, 1976 (Box-folder 54: 14)
  - Conference on Détente speakers, 1976 (Box-folder 54: 15)
  - Solzhenitsyn Society, Sylvia Sarafian materials, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 54: 16)
  - Solzhenitsyn Society Conference on William F. Buckley, 1976 (Box-folder 54: 17)
  - Solzhenitsyn Society publicity, 1976 (Box-folder 54: 18)
- Institute for the Study of Comparative Politics and Ideologies Materials, 1965-1997 (Boxes 55-62)
  - 1997 Institute files, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 55: 1-7)
  - 1993 Institute files, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 56: 1-7)
  - 1992 Institute files, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 57: 1-8)
  - 1990 Institute files, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 58: 1-5)
  - Contributions, 1988 (Box-folder 58: 6-8)
  - Contributions, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 59: 1-8)
  - Contributions, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 60: 1-7)
  - Contributions, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 61: 1-7)
  - Contributions, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 62: 1-10)
- Court Case Materials, 1965-1995 (Boxes 63-71)
  Correspondence, clippings, and court documents regarding the 1978-1985 court case, Dr. Edward J. Rozek v. John A. Topolnicki, Jr.; Larry Reisdorff; Hugh Liddle; the University of Colorado; and the Office of the District attorney for the 18th Judicial District, State of Colorado, Arapahoe County, 865 F.2d 1154 (10th Cir. 1989).
  - Correspondence with Topolnicki, 1981 (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - Witness list, undated (Box-folder 63: 2)
  - Topolnicki's list of potential witnesses, undated (Box-folder 63: 3)
  - Bills, Haddon and Morgan, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 63: 4)
  - Notice of Claim for Damages, 1983 (Box-folder 63: 5)
  - Judge Bellipanni's ruling, 1983 (Box-folder 63: 6)
  - Continuance, 1984 (Box-folder 63: 7)
  - Motion of Censure, undated (Box-folder 63: 8)
  - Motion for Return of Property, 1985 (Box-folder 63: 9)
  - Court Order, Return of Property, 1985 (Box-folder 63: 10)
  - Summons for Contempt of Court Motion, 1985 (Box-folder 63: 11)
  - Inventory list, 1981 (Box-folder 63: 12)
  - Correspondence with Haldon and Morgan, 1971-1983 (Box-folder 63: 13)
  - Colorado Daily, 1980 (Box-folder 63: 14)